Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah.
You may be seated. Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank You, Jesus.
Viewers all over the world, Good Morning to you all.
Let's take our reading to the book of 1 Timothy.
Get home and read from Chapter 1 to the end.
But I will just go through verse 12 there.
The Lord's grace to Paul.
1 Timothy 1: 12: "I thank Christ Jesus our Lord, who has given me strength,
that He considered me trustworthy, appointing me to His service."
Verse 13:
"Even though I was once a blasphemer and a persecutor and a violent man,
I was shown mercy because I acted in ignorance and unbelief."
Hallelujah. Take your reading from verse 1 when you get home -
from verse 1 to the end of 1 Timothy.
You will have so much to learn here.
Hallelujah.
I saw a woman when I was coming
who nearly felt so much discouraged.
I didn't know what happened between the woman, the usher and the worker.
I asked, "Madam, what happened?"
She said, "Oh! This is embarrassment!"
"Oh, embarrassment. Tell me what happened."
"Ah! I was about to come in... They were asking me..."
I said, "Ok. It is like you have so much to tell me, and I'm running out of time.
If you have so much to tell me, I'm running out of time.
There is no way I can listen.
So, let me leave you behind. Let me just...
Okay, after the service, just wait for me.
Forget about whatever happened.
Wait for me after the service. You will be my guest".
She laughed.
She had so much to tell me, and I was running out of time.
That will base my message today.
God cannot use a discouraged servant.
I will not say God cannot bless but let me say God cannot use a discouraged servant.
Are you one of the discouraged servants?
You can get irritated; anything can overwhelm you - just anything.
Maybe somebody messed there.
You know that the atmosphere was friendly but suddenly you begin to sense some nasty odour.
You will not be able to tell your neighbour that somebody has messed.
But you just feel so worried.
"This odour is not good! Somebody is messy!"
Anything can overwhelm you.
Anything can discourage you. You just say, "I'm leaving from here!"
The place you are going to may be even worse than the place you left.
Or even the atmosphere - maybe the weather.
You feel - "Look at the crowd! I don't know when and how this man can manage to attend to everyone!
What has he been doing since morning?"
God cannot use a discouraged servant.
We must overcome such attitude as a Christian.
Satan has a way of making you feel overwhelmed, worry and complain.
You are happy now.
But after a little time - maybe when I am praying for people, I just touched...
Suddenly maybe, I did not touch you.
"Ahh! These people have followed me here today!"
So, if they followed you here, they are the ones saying I shouldn't touch you.
Can you see?
You thought you are the next person to be touched.
Maybe somebody just fell on the floor, and I try to jump to the other side
and I escape you. You say, "Ah! These people have come here again!"
If they come here, would they ask me not to touch you?
If they have power over you, would they have power over me?
Over our Lord Jesus Christ?
So, anything, just anything.
Or maybe, probably, you are expecting to fall during the touching.
You saw your neighbour falling down but you are still standing.
"The thing does not work on me!"
You now begin to look at the people who are turning.
They have touched you and you are still the same.
"Ah! The thing does not work for me!"
God does as He wills.
It is not necessary that you should fall.
When God touches you, you may not even experience anything.
But God is working out the answer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I may even not touch you. I may just see you and leave you.
That is the instruction given - "Don't touch this man. Don't touch this woman".
And the problem is gone without touching you.
It is the instruction. It is not you, it is me.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God cannot use a discouraged servant.
We must overcome such attitude.
So much of this attitude can lead to discouragement.
Even mosquito.
You may be fasting. You may be in the mountain for three days.
Suddenly, one big mosquito just comes.
That is the one that gives you awareness.
What about the one that has been on your body for two hours,
sucking so much blood?
By the time you just move your hand - a pool of blood!
"Oh! This mosquito has carried many diseases!"
A lot of discouragement.
We must confess with our mouth like the Book of Revelation 12:11 says
because what goes around must surely come around.
When we plant a wrong seed, a wrong harvest will surely come.
So, our confession is very important - what you say -
by saying about ourselves what the Bible says about us.
Tell your neighbour: By saying about ourselves what the Bible says about us.
I can't hear you.
By saying about ourselves what the Bible says about us.
We are made to overcome.
The Book of Philippians 4:13 says, "I can do all things through Christ who strengthens me".
By saying about yourself what the Bible says about you.
What does the Bible say about you?
No matter how unsteady your life appears to be, stay steady.
Look at what the Bible says in the Book of 1 Timothy.
Paul warned Timothy not to take a step back when he is sick, attacked, persecuted.
He warned him not to take a step back when he is sick, persecuted or discouraged.
But what is happening to you today?
Remember, what is good for Timothy is equally good for us.
He is warning us not to take a step back while we are facing persecution or crisis
because persecution or whatever you call it is meant for our spiritual benefit.
What do you understand under "take a step back"?
By beginning to complain, looking at Jesus in a bad light.
"Why me of all this? Why me of all that?
I have stopped smoking. I have stopped drinking.
I have been praying. I go to church regularly. Why all this crisis? Why all this? Why all that?"
That is the beauty of our journey to eternal life.
Don't forget, we are not in Heaven. Something must punch us, poke us and test our faith.
He went further by saying,
"Timothy, I know what you are talking about.
You are talking about your setback,
you are talking about your sickness,
you are talking about people that accused you wrongly,
you are talking about this, you are talking about that.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you read that Chapter down, he says that
he messed up big time but God enabled him.
"To mess up big time" means that he has done a lot,
being a persecutor, blasphemor and killer - this and that.
When you look up the word 'enable', it means to support with means, power and knowledge.
When God gives enablement, He gives everything.
Even though you walk through the valley of the shadow of death, you fear not.
Paul Apostle said to Timothy, "I know what it is like to feel like giving up
while sick, facing disappointment or persecution".
He said he knew what it was like but he did not do it; he held on and kept fighting.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He held on and kept fighting.
The beauty of our journey is when you are going and something is there to punch you.
But when you are going and nothing punches you, you are free,
how will you know that the Father you are serving is beautiful.
When you don't sit for an examination and read and sweat
to get a promotion, how will you value the promotion?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you do not read day and night,
in a quiet place reading a lot of textbooks,
sitting for the exam - very tough -
and at the end of the day, you come out brilliantly,
how will you value your certificate?
Why are you proud to introduce yourself as a graduate?
"I have a first degree, PhD."
You are proud to introduce yourself because of what you have gone through to have that.
The beauty of our journey is when something is there to test our faith.
That is the beauty of our journey.
But you never knew this.
Various tests that would have promoted you spiritually,
you failed them because you see them as an attack from the enemy.
You see them as undeserved attacks, undeserved issues
instead of you to welcome that and see that as a friend to move you forward.
Your situations are friends to move you forward.
Your challenges are friends to move you ahead.
Tell your neighbour: Let your situation produce a sense of dependence on God.
I can't hear you.
Let your situation produce a sense of dependence on God.
Let your challenges produce a sense of dependence on God.
I can't hear you.
Again.
Let your challenges produce a sense of dependence on God.
Yes, when you have challenges and those challenges now strengthen your desire for God.
They cause you to look unto God the more.
You are a type that sleeps anyhow, eats anyhow.
But when the challenges come, you go into fasting and pray the more.
It is no longer a challenge but a promotion.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Write this: Let your challenges produce a sense of dependence on God.
When the challenges come - it could be sickness, poverty, hardship, temptation or any foolish thing,
and you quickly look unto God and cry to God, it's meant for promotion.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let your challenges produce a sense of dependence on God.
That is, when we pray, "Oh God, I cannot get along without You; help me!"
He will show Himself stronger.
But when challenges come and it does not produce a sense of dependence on God,
you are leading to the grave.
Challenges come - it could be trouble -
and when that trouble comes, you enter into more trouble again,
more trouble again, more trouble again, more trouble again,
and you never look unto God to get out of that trouble,
you know that this is the end of you.
How do we know promotion is coming?
When challenges come and produce a sense of dependence on God,
you know you are about to be promoted.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
No matter how unsteady your life appears to be, stay steady.
Make this confession your roadmap.
I'm standing on the promise of God.
I am living steady, walking steady, remaining steady in unsteady times.
I choose not to be broke.
I choose not to live in poverty.
I choose not to walk in disappointment.
I choose to walk in God's way.
This world is unsteady.
It is unsteady.
This world you are living in is unsteady.
This is why the Bible says, "In this world, there will be tribulation",
because it is unsteady.
There will be lying, killing, stealing.
You look here - rubbish. You look there - rubbish.
You can't close your eyes when walking.
Even if you close your eyes, your heart will be yearning to smoke, for fleshly desires.
While having your eyes closed, your heart will still yearn for fleshly desires.
So, we are in an unsteady world.
This is why the song says, "This world is not my home".
This world is not my home
I'm just passing through
My treasures are laid up
Somewhere beyond the blue
The angels beckon me from Heaven's open doors
And I can't feel at home in this world anymore
This world is not my home
I'm just passing through
My treasures are laid up
Somewhere beyond the blue
The angels beckon me from Heaven's open doors
And I can't feel at home in this world anymore
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are in an unsteady world.
So, I want to leave you here.
Take this:
When your situation reminds you of God, know that promotion is coming.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour: When your situation reminds you of God, know that promotion is coming.
This is what I mean by our situation is meant for our spiritual benefit.
Our situation produces a sense of dependence on God.
When you have a situation, headache or a doctor says to you,
"Oh! This is serious! This is cancer! This is the liver!",
and this reminds you immediately of God, knowing that promotion is coming.
It is not meant to destroy you but to improve you - your relationship with God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, for other people - their situation does not remind them of God
because that situation is meant to destroy them.
But we - our situation reminds us of God.
That is why it produces a sense of dependence on God.
Our situation reminds us of God.
That situation is to improve us.
When you have a situation - no matter how big that situation -
and it reminds you of God, and you begin to fast and pray,
it is meant to build your relationship and strengthen your desire for God.
Rise up and make this confession your standard from today:
I'm standing on the promise of God.
I'm living steady, walking steady, remaining steady in unsteady times.
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated. Thank you.
So, you think that the ground is smooth for me.
In a little time you hear T.B. Joshua is in America, T.B. Joshua is there.
You say, "Oh, this man! Oh my God, he is not going through what I'm going through!
Look! Everything is just smooth for this man!"
Ooh! The ground is not smooth! It is like this!
Just like you are walking on it, I'm walking on it.
But I'm living steady in an unsteady world.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes, it is not smooth for you.
You go by the standard of the ground.
I'm not going by the standard.
This is how the ground is vibrating and you too go by that vibration.
The ground is vibrating like this but I remain steady.
Whilst it is vibrating, I remain steady.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are living in the same world.
We are eating the same food.
But the difference is that whilst the ground is vibrating - this way -,
you go by that vibration.
Because of that, whatever you carry, seems to fall.
But I walk steady on the vibrating ground.
I say, "No! I refuse to be broke.
I refuse to be poor.
I refuse to live in poverty
and I refuse to walk in discouragement!"
There's a lot of discouragement around but I refuse to walk in discouragement.
But you are walking in discouragement.
So much poverty around - just like you are seeing them, I am seeing them.
But I refuse to live in poverty.
So, we are walking on the same floor - unsteady world.
You are living there - you are there and I am there.
And it is not steady at all but you go by that vibration.
I refuse to.
You can refuse to. The name Jesus is given to you.
"Behold, I give you power to trample on scorpions and snakes."
Let me pray with you.
I pray the Lord gives you a hearing heart.
When situations come - no matter the sickness, disease, temptation,
false accusation or whatever comes to you and you know you are a Christian,
it is time to look unto God, the Finisher of our faith,
and He will show Himself stronger.
So, take this message.
But if you are not a Christian, not a believer, this is not an issue
because for others, their situation destroys them.
Their situation cannot make them look unto God.
Their situation cannot produce a sense of dependence on God.
Rather, their situation takes them away.
You may be seated.
If you are a believer, stop seeing your situation as an enemy.
Let your situation produce a sense of dependence on God.
When we pray, "Oh Lord, I cannot get along without You",
He will show Himself stronger.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you.
Come on. What lesson have you learnt from this message?
I have learnt that I must depend on God.
Whatever challenge or situation I go through, I must depend on God's Word.
Your situation should produce a sense - that is, a feeling that it is time to go to God the more.
You shouldn't leave that for your situation.
You that have the situation should know that you need God the more
I need God the more.
I need You more and more
I need You more and more Jesus every day
That is the voice of situation.
That is the voice of a Christian's situation.
That is the voice of a believer's situation that hears the voice.
Not others - others' situation cannot say this.
But our situation - this is the voice.
Sing again - listen to the voice.
I need You more and more
That is situation.
I need You more and more Jesus every day
I need You more and more
Like a flower needs the rain
Like a bird needs the wind
I need You more and more Jesus every day
Thank you.
You are crying. Why are you crying?
What do you want to tell the world about this message?
I'm so thankful for this message because it spoke into my heart.
For every situation that I face, I mustn't think it is the end of the world.
I must just know that God is there for me and I must just push through
and have the Word of God inside of me.
Thank you.
Any other?
Can I hear from you?
How does the message appeal to you?
This is exactly correct.
My situation demanded to bring me here.
I am a pastor but wherever I go, there are failures.
That failures that come to me are right and correct.
Thank you. He said he is a minister of God.
He looked at situations before now as an enemy but it is a friend.
It is more of our friend than our enemy.
Our situation is more of our friend than our enemy.
Tell your neighbour: Our situation is more of our friend than our enemy.
My situation is more of my friend than my enemy.
Yes, it is more of our friend than our enemy.
That is it.
I know what situation has done in my life - to me.
I'm using my life to preach a message to you.
If not the situation from the beginning of my ministry,
I don't think I would be of this level today.
Your rejection becomes a blessing to me.
Your rejection leads to my closeness to God,
helping me to build my relationship with God,
helping me to have enough time for God.
Yes, your rejection.
At a time you realised that "Oh no! This is a man we should move closer to",
well, I think I have come very close to God.
At the beginning, if you had accepted me, I think I would have had problems.
Big problems - your acceptance would have led to fall, to failure.
Acceptance at the beginning of my ministry - "He is a man of God!" -
today you would not talk about The Synagogue
because then, I was not mature to maintain acceptance.
Now I am mature to maintain acceptance.
You can accept me; I am ready.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know, there is time for everything.
This is why I don't fight back because God allowed you to reject me from the beginning of the ministry.
The rejection from the beginning of the ministry was allowed by God
because God was building me and I was not mature to have all over the world around me then.
I needed some experience.
Oh yes!
You are my friend.
Ok. Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service